So, here's how to rank your SEO content
in Google and AI platforms like ChatGpt.
Step number one, pick a valuable keyword
you can actually compete on. For
example, there's a website ranking in
the top five for some pump repair
Chicago that has a DR of zero. That
means if your website has even a tiny
bit of authority, you'll be able to
outrank them. Use HF's lowest DR filter
to find more keywords with weak
competition. So now that you've selected
a keyword, it's time for step number
two, which is create a knowledge base.
So open chat GBT, go to projects, and
create a new project for your SEO
campaign. This project should act as the
brain behind your SEO content. It's
absolutely critical because it'll help
you create SEO content that's unique and
on brand. Start by creating a document
that includes information like business
basics like brand name, website, phone,
address, etc. what products or services
you offer, what makes your products or
services different compared to the
competition, social proof like
testimonials and Google reviews, and
policies or guarantees. Then upload this
file to your chat GBT project. And if
you want to go to the next level, I
recommend uploading sales call
transcripts, NPS surveys, or anything
that gives the AI context. And once
you're done, ask the AI some questions
about details that are specific to the
documents you've uploaded. It'll then
respond and usually site where it
retrieved that information in the files.
This is what's called grounding, meaning
the AI won't make stuff up. It'll
prioritize the documents you've given it
instead of just going to the web or
hallucinating. Now, moving on to step
number three, which is research to build
an intelligent SEO content brief. This
step is critical for both human and AI
written content. Create a Google sheet
to collect all of your competitors. Then
start with Google by entering your
keyword, exporting the top 10
competitors using the data scraper
Chrome extension and add it to your
sheet. Next, open chat GBT perplexity
and Google AI mode. Then go to the free
AI search query generator on
Rankability. Enter your seed keyword and
the tool will convert it to natural
language prompts. Now run one of these
prompts on all three AI platforms. In
chat GBT, click on sources, then use the
bookmark lid that I'll have below the
video to export all the citations. Add
these to the Google sheet and then
repeat on the other platforms. Now,
export this list of competitors. Open
chat GBT, select agent, and use this
prompt. Copy the report and add it to a
Google doc. Now, for step number four,
create an SEO driven outline. So, go to
the chat GBT project for the campaign
and upload the competitor research
report you just created. Then use this
prompt to create an outline with chat
GBT's thinking model. It'll then produce
an intelligent SEO driven outline that's
relevant and on brand. Which brings us
to step number five. Create your first
draft. If you're using AI, you can just
follow up in the same thread and ask it
to write the draft based on the outline
using this prompt. At this stage, bring
a human into the loop to verify facts.
And then once the copy passes quality
control, it's time for step number six,
which is page design. Most local
businesses just slap content on a page
without designing the page for
conversions. And this is a massive
mistake. If it's a keyword that has
commercial intent, the page should be
built to convert. Go into the same
thread you've created the outline and
draft in and enter the following prompt.
Once the wireframe is done, just send
this off to a designer and get the page
published. Now, this entire SEO content
system might seem like it's incredibly
difficult and complex to set up, but
it's completely automated for you using
Rankability's new copywriter tool. You
just enter your target keyword and
domain, and the system will
automatically detect the intent. Next,
and most important, is to enter or speak
about why this brand is unique and
better than the competition. There's a
meter that will measure the uniqueness
level. Then just add relevant URLs like
the service page and click the toggle to
use the knowledge base you'll have built
within rankability. Copywriter then does
all of the heavy lifting for research.
It finds all of your competitors for
this keyword across nine search engines
and AI platforms. Extracts their content
and creates a content strategy and
outline ready for your approval. Once
you approve, the AI crafts a highly
relevant draft that covers all the
important topics and entities and
includes unique content about your
brand. I'll post a special link below
for you to try it. So, the last question
is, what do you do after you publish
your perfect SEO asset? Well, the work
has just begun because now you have to
do a few things. First, you need to
track your performance. Just throw your
keyword into Rankability's AI search
analyzer and it'll help you track your
performance across AI platforms like
ChatGpt and Google's AI mode. Second,
look for internal linking opportunities.
So, run a screaming frog crawl on your
website, export the report, add a
filter, and go to the title column.
Search for relevant pages where you can
add internal links. If you don't find
many relevant pages, it's a symptom of
poor topical coverage. And that brings
me to step number two in the postpublish
process, which is to make more topically
relevant pages and content. So find your
top competitor, run them through
Screaming Frog, export the report, and
search for pages that are relevant to
your asset. Or if you want to keep it
simple, just use a site: search like
this in Google. In this case, I'm
looking for commercial pages related to
sump pumps. And within a few seconds, I
found Sump pump plumbing inspection and
Sump Pump battery backups, which are
both perfect for supporting our primary
topic. So now, all you have to do is
repeat this same process from this video
for these new pages. And the last step
to creating SEO content that ranks is to
build website authority through backlink
acquisition. So the first technique is
to reverse engineer your competitors.
Just find your top organic search
competitor, run them through HF's link
intersect tool, and you'll see where
they've acquired backlinks. This is your
first group of targets. Next, sign up
for featured, quoted, or HARO. You can
then use your knowledge base to respond
to these press requests on behalf of
your client. And if you want to take
this to the next level, make sure you
conduct a subject matter expert
interview during new client onboarding.
I explain this entire process inside of
Search OS. Lastly, you can use Chat
GBT's agent to automate link prospecting
for pretty much any link type like
donations and guest posts. I'll have the
prompts below the video and watch the
next video to learn what AI SEO skills
you need to master this